荣誉出品
最专业冰火字幕
专注GOT剧集
翻译   唐朝栗子
翻译   梅丽珊卓
翻译   陌客之子
君临 King's Landing
翻译   猇亭将
红堡
Red Keep
校对   泰温公爵
校对   凯冯拉拉兄控
龙石岛
Dragonstone
时间轴   poplar
恐怖堡 Dreadfort
临冬城
Winterfell
后期    poplar    加文·维斯特林
监制    临冬城的狮子   托曼
策划    baozhenyuawabi
特别顾问   屈畅(ccxx)@史诗图书
绝境长城 the Wall
最专业的华语冰火资料站：                         中文维基
http://zh.asoiaf.wikia.com/
百度冰与火之歌贴吧  &  百度权力的游戏贴吧    联合出品
史诗图书  正统奇幻的圣殿
弥林
Meereen
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
衣柜字幕组
更多冰火资讯
请扫码关注“黑城堡”微信平台
微信号：HEICHENGBAO
第四集  The Oathkeeper
守誓剑
我…叫…
My name
灰…虫子
is Grey Worm.
我…来自…
I come from
盛夏…群“倒”
the Summer "Ills."
“岛”
Isles.
盛夏群岛
Summer Isles.
盛夏……群岛
弥桑黛
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安的侍女
我来自纳斯岛
I am from an island called Naath.
灰虫子
无垢者指挥官
他们带走你什么时候?
When they took you?
"他们何时把我带离家乡的?"
"When did they take me?"
在我5岁的时候
I was five years old.
你还记得你的家乡？
You remember your home?
我记得当运奴船把我们带走的时候
I remember when they rowed us away from shore.
沙滩多么的洁白
How white the beaches were.
树木多么的高大
How tall the trees.
我还记得我们村子被烧毁
And I remember my village burning.
烟尘直上云霄
Smoke rising into the sky.
你记得自己的家乡吗?
Do you remember your home?
无垢者
Unsullied.
只记得我是无垢者
Always Unsullied.
之前 什么都记不得
Before Unsullied, nothing.
不要这样想
That's not true.
也许有一天你能回到盛夏群岛呢
Perhaps one day you will return to the Summer Isles.
我并不想回去
I don't want return.
杀死伟主
Kill the Masters.
通用语学的如何了?
How are the lessons coming?
很好 陛下
Very well, Your Grace.
弥桑黛是老师好 女王陛下
Missandei is teacher good, my queen.
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安
“风暴降生” 龙之母
巴利斯坦·赛尔弥
女王铁卫 “无畏的”
看来你还得继续学习
You'll have to continue later.
是时候了
It's time.
你们听到她的话了！
她说她是来解放我们的！
你这蠢货
伟主大人们那么强大
但她会保护我们的
她打败了伟主大人的冠军战士
她有一支强大的军队
你们想下半辈子还做奴隶吗？
我只是想活下来
你也看到他们对无辜孩童做了什么
你觉得他们又会怎么对付我们？
我经历过两次奴隶起义 小鬼
都以相同的结局告终
伟主们获胜 奴隶们死亡
凡人皆有一死
但我可以跟你们保证
哪怕只得一天自由 也胜过一辈子当奴隶
你又是谁？
小人灰虫子
自婴儿时期起被阿斯塔波善主们饲养
训练成无垢者
现在我为丹妮莉丝陛下而战
她是龙之母
锁链破除者
你是无垢者？
你还不会走时就学会如何作战
我们可都不是战士啊！
我们没受过任何训练
而且手无寸铁
在阿斯塔波 三个奴隶侍奉一位善主
兄弟们 自由不是别人能给予你的
如果你们要自由
就必须自已争取
母亲！母亲！母亲！
Mhysa! Mhysa! Mhysa!
母亲！母亲！母亲！母亲！
Mhysa! Mhysa! Mhysa! Mhysa!
母亲！母亲！
Mhysa! Mhysa!
告诉我 乔拉爵士
Remind me, Ser Jorah,
伟主们在路标上钉了多少无辜孩童？
how many children did the Great Masters nail to mileposts?
163个 卡丽熙
163, Khaleesi.
乔拉·莫尔蒙
“大熊”
没错 就是这个数字
Yes, that was it.
陛下 我能跟您进言一句吗？
Your Grace, may I have a word?
现在弥林已属于您
The city is yours.
所有人 都是您的子民
All these people, they're your subjects now.
有时即使是对不义之行
Sometimes it is better to answer injustice
也应该予以宽恕
with mercy.
我要用正义的手段惩戒不义之行
I will answer injustice with justice.
詹姆·兰尼斯特
“弑君者”  御林铁卫队长
你这他妈是干嘛？
What the hell was that?
我正在用你自己的手
That was me knocking your ass to the dirt
波隆
骑士
把你打得屁滚尿流
with your own hand.
不管怎么说 欺负残废
You're a rare talent.
你还真有天才
When you're fighting cripples, anyway.
你的剑法循规蹈矩
You learned to fight like a good little boy.
我敢说 你在疯王背后阴的那一下
I'll bet that thrust through the Mad King's back
姿势肯定很潇洒
was pretty as a picture.
可你到底是在耍帅还是杀人
You want to fight pretty or you want to win?
你跟我弟也都这么讲话？
You talk to my brother this way?
我就这样
All the time.
他习惯了
He got used to it.
你觉得是他干的吗？
Do you think he did it?
不
No.
噢 他当然讨厌那个小崽子
Oh, he hated the little twat, sure.
但谁不讨厌他？
But who didn't?
下毒不是他的风格
And poison's not his style.
就事论事的说 谋杀也不是
Or murder, for that matter.
你这么想知道 干嘛不自己问他？
You want to know for sure, why don't you ask him?
你不打算去见他 是吧？
You haven't been to see him yet, eh?
今天先到此为止
We're done for today.
你老弟有没有告诉过你 我是怎么开始帮他干事的？
Your brother ever tell you how I came into his service?
在鹰巢城比武审判上 你替他出战
You stood for him in his trial by combat at the Eyrie.
对
Aye.
不过是因为艾林夫人下令
But only when Lady Arryn demanded
审判必须当天举行
the trial take place that day.
他本来想选你的
You were his first choice.
他当时任命你为他的代理骑士
He named you for his champion
因为他知道 你会连夜骑马赶来
because he knew you would ride day and night
为他出战
to come fight for him.
这次你会为他出战吗？
You gonna fight for him now?
跟你说实话 这还不算太差
To tell you the truth, this isn't so bad.
四面有墙 还有个夜壶
Four walls. A pot to piss in.
我当时被栓在一根木杆上几个月
I was chained to a wooden post
都快被自己的屎给埋了
covered in my own shit for months.
提利昂·兰尼斯特
“小恶魔”
你在安慰我吗？
Is that supposed to make me feel better?
大概是吧
Maybe a bit.
我很抱歉 没能早点来
I'm sorry I didn't come sooner.
我懂 事态复杂
It's complicated, yes.
- 我们的老姐怎么样了？ - 你觉得呢？
- So how is our sister? - How do you think?
她看着她儿子死在怀里
Her son died in her arms.
只是她儿子？
Her son?
别这样
Don't.
你知道接下来会怎样吗？
You know what's coming?
审判我的弑君之罪 我知道
My trial for regicide. Yes, I know.
我知道他妈的整个国家都认定我有罪
I know the whole bloody country thinks I'm guilty.
我还知道 三个法官其中一个
I know that one of my three judges
早就无数次诅咒我死去
has wished me dead more times than I can count.
这个法官 还是我的亲生父亲
And that judge is my father.
至于瑟曦
As for Cersei,
嗯 她大概正在想法子
well, she's probably working on a way
不经审判也能弄死我
to avoid a trial altogether by having me killed.
既然你自己提到了 她的确这么问过我
Now that you mention it, she did ask.
那我该乖乖转身闭上眼咯？
So, should I turn around and close my eyes?
这取决于你的回答
Depends.
是你做的吗？
Did you do it?
好一对弑君小兄弟
The Kingslayer brothers.
喜欢这称号吗？我还挺喜欢的
You like it? I like it.
你是认真地在问我到底杀没杀你儿子？
You're really asking if I killed your son?
你是认真地在问我到底会不会杀自己的弟弟？
Are you really asking if I'd kill my brother?
我该怎么帮你？
How can I help you?
这简单 放了我呗
Well, you could set me free.
你知道我不能
You know I can't.
那真就没什么好说的了
Then there's really nothing else to say.
你想我怎么办？把守卫都杀了？
What do you want me to do? Kill the guards?
把你藏在马车里 偷偷运出城？
Sneak you out of the city in the back of a cart?
我可是御林铁卫队长
I'm the Lord Commander of the Kingsguard.
抱歉 我忘了
Sorry, I'd forgotten.
御林铁卫做这种事不太妥当
I'd hate for you to do something inappropriate.
不太妥当？
Inappropriate?
你被控弑君 放你逃走是叛国罪
You're accused of killing the king. Freeing you is treason.
可是我啥都没做
Except I didn't do it.
所以我们才要举行审判
Which is why we're having a trial.
审判
A trial.
就算真凶自己跪到铁王座前
If the killer threw himself before the Iron Throne,
承认一切罪行
confessed to his crimes,
还呈上样样铁证
and gave irrefutable evidence of his guilt,
对瑟曦来说也没用
it wouldn't matter to Cersei.
不把我的脑袋插在枪尖上 她是不会罢休的
She won't rest until my head's on a spike.
不只是你的脑袋
Not just yours.
任何人只要能找到珊莎·史塔克 她都承诺授予骑士爵位
She's offering a knighthood to whomever finds Sansa Stark.
不可能是珊莎做的
Sansa couldn't have done this.
她比七国上下任何一个人都更有理由这么做
She had more reason than anyone in the Seven Kingdoms.
难道你认为是个巧合？
Do you think it's a coincidence
乔佛里被杀当晚 她就消失不见了
she disappeared the same night Joffrey died?
不 但是……
No, but...
珊莎不是杀人凶手
Sansa's not a killer.
至少现在还不是
Not yet, anyway.
您要带我去哪儿？
Where are you taking me?
珊莎·史塔克
小恶魔的妻子
我和你的莱莎阿姨就要成婚了
I'm getting married to your Aunt Lysa.
她正在鹰巢城等着我们
She's waiting for us at the Eyrie.
在那里 你会很安全
You'll be safe there.
是您杀了乔佛里吗？
Did you kill Joffrey?
培提尔·贝里席
“小指头”
是我杀了乔佛里吗？
Did I kill Joffrey?
几星期来 我一直留在谷地
I've been in the Vale for weeks.
我知道是您
I know it was you.
那么 是谁帮我实施了这阴谋呢？
And who helped me with this conspiracy?
嗯……君临有唐托斯爵士
Well, there was Ser Dontos.
您利用他帮我逃出来
You used him to get me out of King's Landing,
但您绝不会信任他 让他杀害国王
but you would never trust him to kill the king.
为什么不会？
Why not?
您很聪明 不会信任一个酒鬼
Because you're too smart to trust a drunk.
或许是你丈夫干的
Then perhaps it was your husband.
不是
No.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
我就是知道
I just do.
你是对的
You're right.
他和乔佛里的死没有关系
He wasn't involved in Joffrey's death.
但是你有
But you were.
还记得唐托斯送你的那条漂亮的项链吗？
Do you remember that lovely necklace Dontos gave you?
我敢肯定 你一定没觉察到 宴会之后
I don't suppose you noticed that a stone was missing
上面少了一颗宝石
after the feast.
它是毒药
The poison.
我不明白
I don't understand.
兰尼斯特家族赐给您财富和权力
The Lannisters gave you wealth, power.
乔佛里还让您成了赫伦堡公爵
Joffrey made you the Lord of Harrenhal.
一个没有动机的人 永远成不了嫌疑犯
A man with no motive is a man no one suspects.
永远都要让你的敌人迷惑
Always keep your foes confused.
如果他们看不清你的为人 猜不透你的打算
If they don't know who you are or what you want,
他们就不会知道你真正的目的和打算
they can't know what you plan to do next.
我不相信您说的
I don't believe you.
如果被他们抓到 他们会把您的头插在枪尖上
If they catch you, they'll put your head on a spike
就像对我父亲一样
just like my father's.
您会冒着这样的风险只为了迷惑他们？
You'd risk that just to confuse them?
好多人 从来不敢冒险
So many men, they risk so little.
终其一生都在避开危险之事
They spend their lives avoiding danger.
然后他们死了
And then they die.
为了得到我想要的 什么风险我都敢冒
I'd risk everything to get what I want.
您想要什么？
And what do you want?
一切
Everything.
和兰尼斯特的友谊的确让我收益颇丰
My friendship with the Lannisters was productive.
但是乔佛里
But Joffrey,
他是个恶毒的小男孩 头上还带着王冠
a vicious boy with a crown on his head,
这可不是个可靠的盟友
is not a reliable ally.
谁会信任那样的朋友呢？
And who could trust a friend like that?
那谁又会信任您呢？
Who could trust you?
我不和自己这样的人交朋友。
I don't want friends like me.
我的新朋友做事不会出人意料
My new friends are predictable.
他们行事合乎情理
Very reasonable people.
至于发生在乔佛里身上的事
As for what happened to Joffrey,
我的新朋友求之不得呢
well, that was something my new friends wanted very badly.
没有什么比一份贴心的礼物
Nothing like a thoughtful gift
更能让一份新友谊生生不息了
to make a new friendship grow strong.
我真不敢相信您要离开
I can't believe you're going.
把我一个人留在这儿 和这些人待在一起
Leaving me alone here with these people.
时间差不多了 亲爱的
The time has come, my dear.
没什么事儿能比审判更冗长乏味
There's nothing more tedious than a trial.
大概除了这些花园吧
Except perhaps these gardens.
奥莲娜·雷德温
“荆棘女王”
玛格丽·提利尔的祖母
如果要让我在这些花园里再逛一圈
If I have to take one more leisurely stroll
我宁愿现在就从悬崖上跳下去
through these gardens, I'll fling myself from the cliffs.
你去看过托曼了吗？
Have you been to see Tommen yet?
还没有
No.
他们同意这项婚事了没有？
Have they even agreed to the match?
我什么消息都没听说
No one tells me anything.
你知道的 我并不是一开始
I wasn't originally meant
就被许给你的祖父 罗斯
to marry your grandfather Luthor, you know.
他和我姐姐订了婚
He was engaged to my sister,
就是你的姑婆维奥拉
your great-aunt Viola.
我本来得嫁给某个坦格利安
I was to be given to some Targaryen or other.
那时候人人都想着嫁个坦格利安
Marrying a Targaryen was all the rage back then.
玛格丽·提利尔
王后
但我一看到我要嫁的那一个
But the moment I saw my intended,
长着一张抽筋一样 紧张兮兮的白鼬脸
with his twitchy little ferret's face
和一头滑稽的银发
and ludicrous silver hair,
我就知道 他不合适
I knew he wouldn't do.
所以那天夜里
So the evening
在罗斯向我姐姐求婚之前
before Luthor was to propose to my sister,
我在从刺绣课回家的路上迷了路
I got lost on my way back from my embroidery lesson
一不小心 走到了他的房间里
and happened upon his chamber.
- 看我多迷糊 - 嗯嗯
- How absentminded of me. - Mm-hmm.
第二天早上 罗斯就没能下楼
The following morning, Luthor never made it down the stairs
去向我姐姐求婚  那小子 走都走不动了
to propose to my sister 'cause the boy couldn't bloody walk.
等他恢复了力气 便只想着
And once he could, the only thing he wanted
重温那一夜的体验
was what I'd given him the night before.
我很厉害的
I was good.
非常 非常厉害
I was very, very good.
你比我更厉害
You are even better.
但你得动作快
But you need to act quickly.
瑟曦也许是个恶毒的女人 但她还不算蠢
Cersei may be vicious, but she's not stupid.
很快她就会教她的孩子敌视你
She'll turn the boy against you as soon as she can.
等到你们成亲之后 你再想讨好他就晚了
And by the time you're married, it'll be too late.
幸运的是 摄政太后
Luckily for you, the Queen Regent
现在被分了神
is rather distracted at the moment.
只顾着哀悼她早死的好儿子
mourning her dear departed boy.
指控自己的弟弟为杀人凶手
Accusing her brother of his murder,
虽然他根本没下过手
which he didn't commit.
他还是有可能下手的
Well, he could have done.
他有可能 但他没做
He could have done, but he didn't.
- 祖母大人 您又不知道 - 我当然知道
- You don't know, Grandmother. - But I do know.
你不会真以为我愿意让你嫁给那个小畜生吧？
You don't think I'd let you marry that beast, do you?
什么？我不明白
What? I don't understand.
嘘 别想太多
Shh. Don't you worry yourself about all that.
做你该做的就行
You just do what needs to be done.
刺过来！
Bring it through!
再来
And again.
好的 很好
Very nice. Good.
很多野人会手持两把武器
A lot of wildlings fight with a weapon in each hand.
你们首先要做的就是打掉一把
First thing you want to do
这样他们就不占优势了
is disarm them to try and even the odds.
葛兰
“笨牛” 守夜人游骑兵
让我看看你们的本事
Let's see what you can do.
奥利 你在那看着就好
Olly, you just watch for now.
我能打
I can fight.
琼恩·雪诺
守夜人事务官
你之前握过剑吗？
Have you ever held a sword before?
我以前是村子里最棒的弓手
I was the best archer in our hamlet.
真的！
I was!
我相信你
I believe you.
改天咱们去打兔子
We'll go hunting for rabbits one day.
但现在 好好看 好好学
Rit now, watch and learn.
你俩
You two.
慢慢来 学着打掉对方的武器
Take it slow, try and disarm each other.
洛克
卢斯·波顿的副官
你挺会打
You know how to fight.
但下手应该轻一点
You could have gone easier on him.
那样他就什么都学不到了
He wouldn't have learned anything that way.
雪诺大人
Lord Snow
你以为你在干什么？
What do you think you're doing?
葛兰和我正在训练他们
Grenn and I were helping them.
葛兰是个游骑兵 而你是个事务官
Grenn's a ranger. You're a steward.
艾里沙·索恩
守夜人教头
你之前跟那野人婊子搞在一起的时候可能把这事儿忘了
Maybe you forgot that while you were off with your wildling bitch,
可我没有
but I didn't.
得有人训练他们
Someone has to train them.
但那人不是你
And that someone isn't you.
倒夜壶去
Go find a chamber pot to empty.
赶紧 去啊
Go on. Do it.
你个叛徒的野种
You traitor's bastard.
给我个理由放过你啊
Give me an excuse.
莫尔蒙不在没人护着你了
Mormont's not here to protect you now.
给我回去干活
Get back to work.
马上！
Now!
我说马上！
I said now!
杰诺斯·史林特
守夜人
前都城守备队队长
这野种人气很旺啊 你却不是
The bastard's well-liked. You're not.
你觉得我会在乎人气？我们正在打仗
You think I care if they like me? We're at war.
你现在当权
For now.
但你不能永远代理总司令
But you can't be acting commander forever.
不久就该选举了
There will be a choosing.
那老学士会坚持选出新的司令官
The old maester will insist on it.
听说那小子请求向卡斯特的城堡派兵
You might reconsider
你可以重新考虑一下
his request to march on Craster's.
让叛徒们对付他吧
Let the mutineers take care of Snow.
否则你下半辈子
Or you might be taking orders from him
没准都得听他使唤了
the rest of your life.
私生子 嗯？
A bastard, eh?
你是贵族出身吧
Took you for highborn.
我父亲是贵族
My father was highborn.
我母亲不是
My mother wasn't.
我叫洛克
Name's Locke.
琼恩·雪诺
Jon Snow.
你打得不错
You fight well.
你怎么会来这里的？
What brought you up here?
使命感
A sense of duty.
我想为王国安宁尽一份力
I wanted to do my part for the safety of the realm.
我从前是风暴地的一名护猎员
I was a game warden in the Stormlands.
打了只宝贝山鹑给家里嗷嗷待哺的孩子
Fed a prized partridge to my hungry kids.
结果笨手笨脚被逮住了
I was stupid enough to get caught.
要么来长城 要么少一只手
Chose the Wall over losing my hand.
我琢麽着 来这儿就不用受什么老爷大人的窝囊气了
Figured I wouldn't have to suck up to any highborn cunts here.
快啊 抓紧点
Come on, get on with it.
你们等什么呢 等夏天来吗？
What are you waiting for? Summer?
但我好像错了
Guess I was wrong.
瑟曦·兰尼斯特
太后
您叫我 陛下？
You sent for me, Your Grace?
陛下
Your Grace.
瞧你多正经啊
How formal of you.
托曼房外安排了几名御林铁卫？
How many Kingsguards are posted outside Tommen's door?
柏洛斯爵士今夜执勤
Ser Boros is on duty tonight.
- 明晚我想是—— - 只有一人？
- Tomorrow I believe-- - So one?
你就安排一个人来保护未来的国王？
You have one man guarding the future king?
我保证托曼是安全的
I promise you Tommen's safe.
我们日夜保护他
We're protecting him.
就像你保护乔佛里那样？
The way you protected Joffrey?
为什么凯特琳·史塔克会放了你？
Why did Catelyn Stark set you free?
- 什么？ - 我已经想了好几个月
- What? - I've been wondering for months.
自从那头老母牛放你回君临我就开始琢磨
Ever since that great cow brought you back to the capital.
她为什么放了你？
Why did she set you free?
你知道为什么
You know why.
她以为我能把女儿还给她
She'd hoped I'd send her daughters back to her.
是她以为 还是你发誓？
She hoped or did you promise?
我以新旧诸神之名发了誓
I swore by all the gods
如果她的女儿们还活着 我就要把她们还给她
that if her daughters were alive, I'd return them to her.
你对敌人发了神圣的誓言
So you made a sacred vow to the enemy.
我只想回到你身边
I wanted to get back to you.
难道我应该让她滚蛋吗？
Should I have told her to fuck off?
你不是认真的 是吗？
You didn't mean it, then?
你对凯特琳·史塔克毫无忠诚可言？
You have no loyalty to Catelyn Stark?
凯特琳·史塔克已经死了
Catelyn Stark's dead.
那如果我要你现在离开君临去找珊莎
So if I told you to leave the capital right now and find Sansa,
如果我要你找到那杀人不眨眼的小婊子
if I told you to find that murderous little bitch
把她的脑袋给我带回来
and bring me her head,
你会照办吗？
would you do it?
我知道你去见提利昂了
I know you went to see Tyrion.
那怪胎谋杀了我们的儿子
That creature who murdered our son.
我必须去见他
I had to see him.
我必须自己去了解真相
I had to know for myself.
然后呢？
And?
不是他干的 瑟曦
He didn't do it, Cersei.
你总是同情他
You've always pitied him.
同情我们的小弟
Our poor little brother.
想想吧 他被整个世界侮辱
Abused by the world.
被父亲和姐姐鄙视
Despised by his father and sister.
一旦有机会 他会把我们全杀了
He'd kill us all if he could.
我要托曼房外日夜都有四个人值守
I want four men at Tommen's door day and night.
就这样吧 队长大人
That will be all, Lord Commander.
突击爵士？
Ser Pounce?
托曼·拜拉席恩
乔佛里之弟 王储
你是怎么绕过御林铁卫的？
How did you get past the Kingsguard?
御林铁卫 哈
Kingsguard.
我觉得你不该在这儿
I don't think you're supposed to be here.
妈妈不许我晚上会客
Mother doesn't allow me to have visitors at night.
我不是客人 陛下
I'm not a visitor, Your Grace.
据说我将是您的新娘
Word has it I'm to be your bride.
您知道吗？包办婚姻的主角
Did you know that people in arranged marriages
通常直到婚礼那天才第一次见面
often never meet until their wedding day?
在我们决定共度余生之前
Before we decide to spend our lives together,
我们首先应该了解彼此
we ought to get to know one another.
不是吗？
Don't you think?
是啊
Yes.
可如果妈妈发现了——
But if my mother found out--
就当是我们的秘密 嗯？
It can be our secret. Hmm?
如果我们要结为夫妻
If we're going to be man and wife,
我希望我们跟她之间能有秘密可言
we'll have a few secrets from her, I hope.
那么 陛下......
So, Your Grace...
嗯？
Yes?
告诉我一个你的秘密吧
Tell me a secret.
突击爵士
托曼的猫
你好 真是个好伙伴 是吧？
Hello. Aren't you a proper fellow?
这是突击爵士
That's Ser Pounce.
真帅气
Very handsome.
乔佛里不喜欢他
Joffrey didn't like him.
他曾说要把它活剥了
He threatened to skin him alive
把内脏掺进我的食物里
and mix his innards up in my food
让我不知不觉把它吃下去
so I wouldn't know I was eating him.
那可真残忍
That's very cruel.
我觉得你并不残忍
You don't strike me as cruel.
嗯
No.
我并不残忍
I don't think I am.
那就好
That's a relief.
那你知道我们结婚意味着什么吗？
Because you know what happens when we marry?
我们会在大圣堂发下誓言
We say our vows in front of the high septon.
在仪式过后 会有一场盛宴
And after the ceremony, there's a feast.
结婚以后 我就是你的了
When we marry, I become yours.
永远都是
Forever.
时候不早了
It's getting late.
我该走了
I should go.
我还可以再来看你吗？
May I come and visit you again?
那就好
All right, then.
别忘了
Remember,
我们的小秘密
our little secret.
"詹姆·兰尼斯特爵士
"Ser Jaime Lannister.
年仅十六岁时即受封为骑士 不久被任命为御林铁卫
Knighted and named to the Kingsguard in his 16th year.
君临之战中
At the sack of King's Landing,
弑君伊里斯二世于铁王座之下
murdered his king Aerys II.
后被新国王劳勃·拜拉席恩赦免
Pardoned by Robert Baratheon.
布蕾妮·塔斯
“美人”
自此人称“弑君者”
Thereafter known as the Kingslayer."
记录这些是队长的责任
It's the duty of the Lord Commander to fill those pages.
而我的部分还没有写完
And there's still room left on mine.
瓦雷利亚钢剑
Valyrian steel.
嗯
Mmm.
它是你的了
It's yours.
我不能接受它
I can't accept this.
它是用奈德·史塔克的剑重铸的
It was reforged from Ned Stark's sword.
你要用它来保护奈德·史塔克的女儿
You'll use it to defend Ned Stark's daughter.
你发誓要将史塔克家的女儿们送回母亲身边
You swore an oath to return the Stark girls to their mother.
史塔克夫人已死
Lady Stark's dead.
艾莉亚很可能也死了
Arya's probably dead, too,
但你还有机会找到珊莎 保护她平安
but there's still a chance to find Sansa and get her somewhere safe.
我还有样东西送你
I've got something else for you.
希望我弄对了尺寸
I hope I got your measurements right.
我会找到她
I'll find her.
为了凯特琳夫人
For Lady Catelyn.
也为了你
And for you.
我差点忘了
I almost forgot.
还有份礼物呢
I have one more gift.
波德瑞克·派恩
提利昂的侍从
我不需要侍从
I don't need a squire.
你当然需要
Of course you do.
他会拖累我
He'll slow me down.
我弟弟欠他个人情 他在这里不安全
My brother owes him a debt. He's not safe here.
你会保护他的 这是骑士精神
You're keeping him from harm. It's chivalry.
我不会拖累您的 爵——
I won't slow you down, ser--
小姐
my lady.
我保证会好好服侍您
I promise I'll serve you well.
瞧见没？他是个好小子 你们会好好相处的
See? He's a good lad. You'll get along.
这是提利昂大人的谢礼
Compliments of Lord Tyrion.
他在黑水河之战用的斧子
His axe from the Blackwater.
你还等着亲一口么？
What are you waiting for, a kiss?
快去把小姐的马备好
Ready the lady's horse.
好剑都有好名字
They say the best swords have names.
有主意吗？
Any ideas?
守誓剑
Oathkeeper.
再见 布蕾妮
Good-bye, Brienne.
驾 驾
Come on, move.
我当初真不该带她走
I should never have taken her away.
- 她在这里不安全 - 她在那里也不安全
- She wasn't safe here. - She's not safe out there.
我本该知道的
I should have known.
山姆威尔·塔利
“杀手” 守夜人事务官
你告诉过我们长城南边也有野人
You told us there were wildlings south of the Wall.
如果他们在劫掠那些小村落 鼹鼠村可能就是下一个目标
If they're raiding the smaller villages, Mole's Town could be next.
- 黑城堡也可能是下一个目标 - 我该回去接吉莉
- Castle Black could be next. - I should go back for Gilly.
我们有令在身 不能离开城堡
We have orders. No one's to leave the castle.
我记得你曾经抗命南下去帮助罗柏
I remember when you disobeyed orders and rode south to help Robb.
我也记得是谁追上我然后把我带回来
And I remember who came after me and brought me home.
我知道这有多难 山姆 相信我
I know how hard it is, Sam, believe me.
当你跟我讲布兰越过长城时
When you told me about Bran going beyond the Wall,
我唯一的念头就是赶快振作起来
all I could think about was getting my strength back
好出去找他
so I could go and find him.
我真希望能说服他一起回来
I wish I could have convinced him to come back with me.
我尽力了 真的 我尽力了
I tried. Really, I did.
他们能跑多快？
How fast could they travel?
一个傻子拉着雪橇 上面坐一个残废的孩子？
A crippled boy being pulled on a sledge by a simpleton?
我不知道
I don't know.
他们会经过野人的村落
They'd pass wildling villages.
可以找到歇脚的地方
They could try to find shelter at one of them.
野人们都追随曼斯去了
The wildlings have joined up with Mance.
这些村落或者歇脚的地方不会有人的
Every village or sheltered place will be deserted.
除了……
Except...
卡斯特的城堡
Craster's?
你觉得布兰会不会发现……
You think Bran might have found--
雪诺
Snow.
抱歉打扰了
I don't mean to interrupt.
索恩要见你
Thorne wants to see you.
我批准你们
Your foray to Craster's Keep,
突击卡斯特城堡的计划
I'll sanction it.
但我不会命令任何人与你同行
But I won't order anyone to go with you.
你得找志愿者
Volunteers only.
谢谢你 艾里沙爵士
Thank you, Ser Alliser.
弟兄们
Ahem, brothers.
我要越过长城前往卡斯特的城堡
I'm going beyond the Wall to Craster's Keep.
我要抓住据守在那里的叛徒 或者杀掉他们
I'm going to capture the mutineers holed up there or kill them.
派普尔
“派普” 守夜人
我需要志愿者与我同行
I'm asking for volunteers to come with me.
艾迪森·托勒特
“忧郁的艾迪” 守夜人事务官
这里和卡斯特的城堡之间是60英里的荒野
There's 60 miles of wilderness between here and Craster's
还有正在逼近的曼斯·雷德的大军
and Mance Rayder has an army bearing down on us,
但我们必须这么做
but we have to do this.
我们的存亡取决于
Our survival may depend on
我们能否在曼斯之前找到这些叛徒
us getting to these mutineers before Mance does.
他们了解长城 了解我们的布防
They know the Wall. They know our defenses.
如果曼斯知道了这些情报 我们就完蛋了
If Mance learns what they know, we're lost.
如果这还不够的话
But if that's not enough,
那么想想看
then consider this.
如果守夜人彼此真的是兄弟
If the Night's Watch are truly brothers,
那么莫尔蒙总司令大人就是我们的父亲
then Lord Commander Mormont was our father.
他把一生奉献给守夜人
He lived and died for the Watch
却被自己的手下背叛
and he was betrayed by his own men.
背后被懦夫捅了刀子
Stabbed in the back by cowards.
他不该落得如此下场
He deserved far better.
我们现在能做的是去为他讨回公道
All we can give him now is justice.
有谁愿意跟我去？
Who will join me?
我可不能让一个新兵跑到长城北面去
I can't let a recruit come north of the Wall.
那就让我先宣誓吧
Then let me say my vows.
如果你要奔赴战场
If it's a fight you're heading for,
那么你需要一个会打仗的人
then you need men who know how.
谢谢 弟兄们
Thank you, brothers.
不 别
No, don't.
别 求你了
Don't, please.
卡尔·坦纳
守夜人叛徒
求你了别这样 啊
Please don't. Ow!
你把我弄疼了
You're hurting me.
琴酒巷的卡尔·坦纳
Karl Tanner from Gin Alley
拿杰奥·他妈的·莫尔蒙
drinking wine from the skull
的天灵盖喝酒
of Jeor fucking Mormont.
总司令大人 有何吩咐？
Any command for us, Lord Commander?
什么？
What's that?
把她们操到死？
Fuck 'em till they're dead?
听到了吗 小子们？
Did you hear that, boys?
操到死
Fuck 'em till they're dead.
雷斯特
Rast.
出去喂那头畜生
Go outside and feed the beast.
我们应该杀掉它
We should kill that thing.
你他妈的应该闭嘴
You should shut your fucking hole,
小丑逼
ugly little cunt.
你他妈看上去就像个尿泡
You look like a fucking ballsack.
雷斯特
守夜人叛徒
丑货 看看你那贱德行
Ugly. Look at your stupid cunt face.
老子撒泡尿能把五个你都淹了
I could piss in any gutter and soak five of you.
知道老子在君临城杀一个人能挣多少钱吗？
Know how much they paid me to kill a man in King's Landing?
七枚银鹿
Seven silvers.
只要告诉老子名字 那个人就别想再见着太阳了
They told me a man's name and that man never saw daylight again.
那些个人渣 没一个能逃得掉
None of them cocksuckers got away from me.
老子九岁以来打架就没输过
Haven't lost a fight since I was nine.
也许时候到了
Maybe it's time.
你怎么看 嗯？
What do you think, eh?
也许你能打败老子
Maybe you're the man.
嗯 贱人？
Eh, cunt?
我可打不赢你
I wouldn't stand a chance.
我们都不行
None of us would.
老子他妈在琴酒巷就是个传说
I was a fucking legend in Gin Alley.
他妈的传说
A fucking legend!
老子能干翻任何一个骑士——
I would take any knight--
甭管是谁 甭管啥时候
any knight, any time.
那些该死的缩在板甲里的娘们 该死的软蛋
Fucking cunts in steel plate. Fucking cowards.
- 献给众神的礼物 - 献给众神的礼物
- A gift for the gods. - A gift for the gods.
献给众神的礼物
A gift for the gods.
这他妈是啥
What the fuck is that?
卡斯特最后一个孩子 一个男孩
Craster's last child. A boy.
老子得怎么处理他？
What am I supposed to do with him?
卡斯特是怎么处理的？
What did Craster do with 'em?
趁着崽儿有本事杀爹之前先宰了？
Kill 'em before they could grow up and do the same to him?
成
All right.
少一个人抢饭碗也好
Don't need another mouth to feed.
- 递过来 - 卡斯特没有杀掉他们
- Hand him over. - He didn't kill them.
- 而是献祭他们 - 给谁？
- He offered them. - To who?
给众神
To the gods.
哦 异鬼啊
The white walkers.
献给众神的礼物 献给众神的礼物
A gift for the gods. A gift for the gods.
闭嘴！
Shut up!
既然……
So...
卡斯特这么做管用的话……
if it worked for him...
异鬼想要什么咱还是给什么
Let's give the walkers what they want.
雷斯特 交给你了
Rast is headed that way.
白灵
琼恩·史塔克的冰原狼
红眼畜生
Pink-eyed fuck.
渴了吗？
You thirsty?
操！
Fuck!
阿多
Hodor.
临冬城的马僮
听到了吗？
Do you hear that?
夏天
布兰·史塔克的冰原狼
梅拉·黎德
布兰·史塔克的保护者
是不是个婴儿？
Is that a baby?
它来了
It's coming.
玖健·黎德
拥有绿之视野的男孩
我去看看
I'm going out there.
不 我们不能分开
No, we need to stay together.
我去了
I'm going.
布兰·史塔克
易形者
- 布兰 布兰 - 阿多 阿多
- Bran. Bran. - Hodor. Hodor.
- 阿多 - 布兰 发生什么事了？
- Hodor. - Bran, what happened?
夏天受伤了 他们用陷阱抓住了它
Summer, he's hurt. They've caught him in a trap.
谁设的陷阱？
Who?
我没看见 但他们还抓住了我哥哥的狼
I didn't see, but they have my brother's wolf.
他们抓住了白灵
They have Ghost.
他们是守夜人
They're Night's Watch.
看
Look.
琼恩也许在那里
Jon might be here.
如果琼恩在 为啥把狼关进笼子？
If Jon was here, why would they put his wolf in a cage?
他们也许曾经是守夜人 现在不是了
They might have been Night's Watch once, not anymore.
我们在这里不安全 得走了
We're not safe here. We need to go.
不
No.
布兰 我们现在得走了
Bran, we need to go now.
救不出夏天我不会走
I'm not leaving without Summer.
你能回忆下笼子在哪吗？
Can you remember where the cage was?
城堡的东面
The east side of the keep.
如果我一时没回来 我们在……
If I'm not back soon, we'll meet--
阿多
Hodor.
阿多 阿多
Hodor. Hodor.
阿多
Hodor.
如果我有你这块头 我他妈就是这个世界的王了
If I was your size, I'd be king of the fucking world.
扶他起来
Help him up.
还真不错
This is nice.
上好的皮革
Fine leather.
你不是野人
You're no wildling.
重要人物 贵族
Important. Highborn.
你是谁？
Who are you?
看 在老家那边
You see, where I come from,
像老子这种贱民扇你这种少爷一个耳光
a commoner like me slaps a little lord like you,
得掉一只手
I'd lose my right hand.
不过我们离家远着呢 不是吗？
But we're a long way from home, aren't we?
还有你们俩
And the two of you,
塞外的美人们
fancy-looking folks north of the Wall
在树林里爬行
creeping through the woods.
很奇怪啊
Isn't that a bit odd?
老子喜欢你的卷发
I like your curly hair.
跟我妈的头发一样
My mom had curls like that.
漂亮的棕色卷发
Beautiful brown curls.
你们干嘛拖着一个残废孩子跑到这里来？
Why'd you drag a crippled boy all the way up here?
看来你们没玩过这游戏
See you haven't played this game before.
一个贵族人质
A highborn hostage,
是很值钱的
that's valuable.
但是三个的话
But three of them,
就是三张嘴要喂
that's a lot of mouths to feed.
他他妈的怎么了
What the fuck's wrong with him?
上这来
Come here.
别 求你
No, please.
求你 让我帮他
Please. Please, let me help him.
- 你是谁？ - 求你
- Who are you? - Pleas.
- 你是谁？ - 我是布兰登·史塔克
- Who are you? - I'm Brandon Stark!
我是临冬城的布兰登·史塔克
I'm Brandon Stark of Winterfell.
是琼恩·雪诺的弟弟
It's Jon Snow's brother.
是梅拉 是梅拉 我在这儿呢
It's Meera. It's Meera. I'm right here.
老子还头疼今天怎么熬呢
And I thought this was gonna be another boring day.
我在这儿呢
I'm right here.
衣柜字幕组出品